David Orquera

Data Engineer

Pilar, Buenos Aires, Argentina (GMT-3)

(+54) 9 11 7360-1641

david orquera@hotmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidorquera/

Portfolio

Data Engineer with more than 11 years of experience in BI projects, collaborating in the development life cycle from end to end. Thanks to my experiences, I have developed excellent analytical skills, customer orientation, teamwork and very good communication.

EXPERIENCE

Data Engineer, Gregario SpA (September 2022 – March 2023)

letter of recommendation

- Improved loading times by 50% by optimizing stored procedures and improvements in the DW model.
- Implement the creation of a data quality so that clients can verify the update of the data. I participated in the assembly of the SP in PostgreSQL and then the visualization in Tableau.

Technological stack: PostgreSQL, Python, Tableau.

Full Stack Developer, Jobint (May 2022 – June 2023)

letter of recommendation

- Optimized by 75% the information processing times in the process management of the system dedicated to the control of publication plans by improving internal processes and allowing more visibility of the plans by country.
- Contributed to the development of systems from scratch with various ReactJs, NodeJs and NestJs programming languages using the best practices and improving the user experience.

Technological stack: API Rest, JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJs, NodeJs, NestJs, Redux, Redux-toolkit, Sagas, Microservicios, GCP, Express, PostgreSQL, MySQL, HTML, CSS, material-UI, styled-component, GitHub, Jira.

BI Coordinator Leader, Aerolíneas Argentinas (June 2014 – July 2020)

- Optimized the information processing time for flight tracking by 90%, allowing for a better understanding of issues that
 may affect operations. I developed the end-to-end process, culminating in an online control dashboard for visualization
 on a monitor.
- Developed an end-to-end analysis for the company's internal audit system. Based on this analysis, indicators, reports, and dashboards generated, which subsequently enabled improvements in internal audit procedures.

Technological stack:PostgreSQL, SQL Server, Oracle, Informix, JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, Microstrategy, Power BI, SSIS, SSRS, QlikSence, ETL, Scriptella, XML.

Data Architect, CEICOM *(November 2010 – December 2013)*

- Optimized the DW structure to develop new dashboards that offered to clients. Sales of the new boards made.
- Creation of different reports and dashboards in Microstrategy, restricting permissions per user.

Technological stack: SQL Server, Oracle, Microstrategy, SSIS, ETL.

Jr. BI Consultant, Blue Patagon (November 2009 – October 2010)

- Improves by 50% the processing time of the information of the ETL processes for the assembly of the revenue accounting data.
- Correction in improvements of the declared dimensions to maintain the consistency in the data.

Technological stack: SQL Server, Microstrategy, SSIS, ETL.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Java, C++.

Frameworks: ReactJS, NodeJS, Redux, NestJS.

Database: PostgreSQL, SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB.

Visualizers: Microstrategy, Tableau, Power BI.

Tools: SSIS, Docker, Kubernetes, GitHub, Jira, Slack, Spark, GCP, Hadoop, Nifi, Hive, Airflow, PySpark, BigQuery, Cloud Storage, Cloud SQL, BigTable, Cloud Composer, Cloud Functions, Sqoop, HDFS, Apache HBase, Meltano, Command Shell.

Agile: Scrum, Kanban, Looker.

Languages: English (B1), Spanish (native)

EDUCATION

Técnico Superior en Programación, Universidad Tecnológica Nacional – *Pacheco, Bs As, Argentina, 2012*.

COURSES

Bootcamp de Data Engineering, Escuela de Datos Vivos – *Buenos Aires, Argentina, June – September 2023.*JS Coding Bootcamp: Full Stack Developer, Plataforma 5 – *Buenos Aires, Argentina, April 2022.*